OBJECTIVE

I am a self-taught programmer, who took on the challenge to switch careers after working many years in the product development and marketing field. Grow passion for engineering from the previous experience, and take action to reach my goal. Currently, I am seeking for a software engineer role, can't wait to dive into the industry.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Dallas, Naveen Jindal Management School	Richardson, TX
Master of Science, Marketing; GPA 3.7/4.0	2014-2016
Xi'an International Studies University	Xi'an, China
Bachelor of Arts, Philology of Spanish; Rank 10/100	2008-2012
Universidad de La Habana, Cuba(Exchange Student)	2008-2009
Universidad de Salamanca, Spain(Exchange Student)	2010-2011

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Technical skill**: Python; SQL; C; HTML; CSS; JavaScript; SAS; Excel VBA; Google Analytics; Google AdWords; Omniture; Ad-Hoc Analysis; SPSS; SAP; Tableau; IBM Core-metrics
- · Language: Mandarin-native; English-fluent; Spanish-fluent; Portuguese-basic

COURSEWORK

- Coursera: Programming for Everybody (Python); Python Data Structures; Using Databases with Python; Using Python to Access Web Data; Capstone: Retrieving, Processing and Visualizing Data with Python; Excel/VBA for Creative Problem Solving
- Harvard Online Education: CS50 Introduction to Computer Science; CS50 Web Programming with Python and JavaScript
- UT Dallas: Database Management; Spreadsheet Modeling and Analytics

PROJECTS

- Stock Trade website (<u>link</u>): implemented a website via which users can "buy" and "sell" stocks, using Flask, Python, HTML, CSS, to design and develop the website and SQL database to keep track of users' login and transaction records
- Mastermind Game (link): implemented a mastermind game using Python, which can be played by a user against the computer to guess a number-combinations.
- Homepage project (link): built a homepage that introduces my-self, using HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Image filter (link): developed an image processing program that applies filters to BMPs using C
- Ultimate file organizer (link): created a tool that consolidates and combines information from multiple spreadsheets into one spreadsheet using Excel Visual Basic

EXPERIENCE

OIGETIT(Oh! I Get it!) Fake News Filter Marketing Analyst

Menlo Park, CA

2017.9-2019.5

- Daily content posting on social media platforms, daily QA check news feeds on demo website and report bug feeds
 or broken links to the backend, collaborate with backend team and management team to prepare the pre-launch
 work
- Increased Facebook Page followers' conversion rate from 1.87% to 5.03% by posting users most interesting news topics at times when users are highly active on Facebook which was analyzed data through Facebook Insight;
- Conduct competitive analysis about Fake news apps on the market to know the competitors and also help us to develop the value proposition
- Researched related and relevant worldwide tech conferences for speaking opportunities to promote OIGETIT, collaborate with the organizers to settle down schedule and accommodations, established potential investor relationships through communications with event partners

Cupertino City Hall-G50 Global Smart City Summit *Marketing Manager*

Cupertino, CA 2017.9-2018.4

- Planned and organized a 500 city officials event: analyze and research city officials' goals to attend the Summit, conduct research on latest Smart City technology, segment, and pair SC technology to goals to correspondent Summit sections, design invitation letters and agenda, invite the best candidate keynote speakers to present at the Summit
- Successfully invited 15 company founders and executives from industries to speak at the G50 GSCS, including Google, Dell, NVIDIA, Verizon, Palo Alto Networks, etc., and finalized schedule, logistics, and accommodations with speakers' team
- Reached out to sponsoring organizations to support the Summit which consist of 40% of the total Summit funding
- Communicated with internal marketing and planning team and external vendors, creation of marketing materials and social media content, on-site production

Law Offices of Jean D. Chen Marketing Assistant

San Jose, CA 2016.9-2017.6

 Worked closely with clients to tailor services to their specifications, developed strong interpersonal and communication skills by collaborating with clients, and maintained and updated client records in the database, gained organizational skills and effective working skills by directly assisting to three paralegals and marketing director

Baidu, Inc.
International Portal Search Product Manager — Global Product Department

Beijing, China

2012.1-2013.8

- Lead search engine market research on competitors in 7 different global markets to determine target markets and market opportunities of Portal Search using comScore query data
- Integrated our team to deliver Portal Search Portuguese version online in Brazil occupying all search traffic from Baidu's search homepage "Hao123" and grew users from zero to 2 million within one month, equalizing 2 times of the original KPI
- Reported on search market trends, like Knowledge graph, and on steps to maintain Baidu's competitive edge of processing query and providing precise results in the search engine industry
- Cooperated closely with Engineering to determine the best technical implementation method, using Chinese version structure embedded with NLP for multi-language and feasible execution schedules

CERTIFICATIONS

- Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python)-Coursera Course Certificates
- Python Data Structures-Coursera Course Certificates
- Excel/VBA for Creative Problem-Solving Specialization-Coursera Course Certificates
- Google AdWords
- Google Analytics